Cynthia Huallanca

17205 SW 88 Avenue Palmetto Bay, FL 33157 | +1 (305) 804-5510 | cynthiahuallanca@gmail.com

Summary

Enthusiastic professional with outstanding attention to details and problem-solving skills. Ability to adapt and prioritize, passioned for challenges. Analyst and software development experience. Want to see some of my work? Go to my Portfolio and website!

Experience

ESDINAMICO CIA. LTDA.

Data Analyst Consultant | Ecuador

Mar 2019 - Present

- · Offered insights and actionable information by analyzed and interpreted business data
- · Used business data with the goal of answering questions and solving problems. Designed reports and dashboards.

DATA TECH USA INC.

Excel Consultant | Miami, USA

Mar 2018 - Mar 2018

• Designed and trained Sales team in 'Excel for Sales course' allowing to improve their revenue by developing an efficient work process and gaining knowledge directly related with daily routine.

AZTEC EXCHANGE

Business Development Manager, Americas | Miami, USA

May 2017 - June 2018

Responsible for generating new business with debtors in the accounts receivable financing industry and driving big volume customers to obtain the sale of invoices of companies in LATAM. Calling/meeting C-level to obtain contracts.

- · Best seller, US\$1.9million in 5 months, plus new business line in Peru with US700,000 in new revenue
- · Teamwork with marketing, support with ideas/strategies for customer engagement, improving customer perception

Senior Client Management | Miami, USA

Apr 2016 - May 2017

Responsible to engage new market of Latin America by selling the ePayMe Platform Value Proposition as Financial Service including risk management, risk assessment and compliance of clients.

- · Handled portfolio of +200 customers with +40% of client acceptance with different currency type and cross-border business
- · Developed techniques to increase new customers rate, based on market data analysis
- · Supported It team with tests and business reports to update internal system and platform

AMINORTE SA

Data Analyst | Santiago, Chile

Jun 2014 – Feb 2016

 $\label{lem:constraints} \textbf{Responsible for extracting, cleaning and interpreting business and market data}.$

- Increased sales revenue in 15% by presenting a pricing strategy after web scraping using Selenium in collaboration with IT team. Cleaned, analyzed and interpreted data obtaining many other competitive advantages.
- · Incremented in 70% client renewal of software products by analyzing market and implemented new relationship strategy

Project Manager (Data Migration) | Santiago, Chile

Oct 2012 - Jul 2014

Orchestrated an initiation, planning, design, execution, monitoring, controlling and procurement of the migration into new ERP.

- · Restructured rigid process and integrated them into the new ERP, decreasing response time to client logistics process by 60%
- · Process completed within 8 months, by managing IT team, including training personnel
- · Cleaned, transformed old data to migrate into new ERP

Education

UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI | Miami, USA

In progress

Business Analyst

UNIVERSITY OF CONCEPCION | Concepcion, Chile

May 2012

Bachelor's Degree Auditing and Accounting. Major: Science in Business Administration

Skills

Advanced Statistics and Excel, API Interactions, HTML /CSS (Bootstrap), GitHub, HubSpot CRM, JavaScript (D3.js, Leaflet.js), NoSQL (MongoDB), Power BI, Python (NumPy, Pandas, etc.), R, Social Media Mining, SQL, Visual Basic Scripting. Fluency in Spanish and English.